During the day
昼間に
I saw these two standing on Yiyang's city walls
城頭でお二方を拝見仕り候
They're not enemies
敵にあらぬと存じ申す
You two
何ゆえ
Why are you dressed like this?
此の装いか？
Confidential
ああ
I understand
秘密なり、存じ申した
I am the commander
あたしは統領・劉大刀の
Liu Dadao's granddaughter
孫娘にて
I'm Liu Nian
劉念と申す
This is Uncle Qiu
こちらが邱叔
Grandfather's capable deputy
祖父の副将に候
Yiyang garrison deputy general Xie Xuan
弋陽守備軍副将・謝玄に候
By my general's orders
我が主に命ぜられ
Come to discuss with General Liu
義軍の順番入城を
The matter of volunteers entering in groups
協議せんと存じ奉る
Specific details
具体的なこと
Follow me
ついて参れ、
I'll take you to see grandfather
祖父に会おう
Those two
お二人のうち
One of them said
一人は
He's the Yiyang garrison deputy general
副将と名乗り
The other didn't mention
もう一人は名乗らず候が
But I think something's off
何か怪しき面相にて候
What's off?
何か怪しきと？
Didn't I treat everyone's
かつて我、皆に薬草を調合し凍傷を治し候
Frostbite on hands and feet?
皆に薬草を調合し凍傷を治し候
His hands
彼の手は
Look different from ours
我らと異なる
What?
何か異なるの？
He has six fingers
六本指か？
Your general pays respects to Prince of Jin
晋王殿下に拝謁を！
Grandfather
おじいちゃん？
Pay
殿……
Respects to Your Highness
殿下に拝謁を！
Commander Liu
劉統領
Why would I need to hide
我がいかにして身を隠し
To come out and see you?
お会いせしを
Do you understand
お前よくお分かりか？
This
これは…
In the volunteer army
義軍の中
There are many eyes
雑多な者多しと申すか？
A force of nearly ten thousand
万人に近き部隊
Can you guarantee
そなたは
You know each person's background?
各人の素性を悉く知り得るか？
In this volunteer army
義軍に
There's more than just my group
あらず一つの勢力ばかりにあらず
Everyone just came together temporarily
皆、臨時の集結に候……
So
だから
I cannot let you into the city
僕はお前らを入城させ得ぬ！
If in the volunteer army
義軍中に
There are Wuzhao spies
鄔奴の回し者あらば
Taking advantage of the chaos
城内に潜みて
Once they enter and cause Yiyang to fall
弋陽城を陥し
The northern expedition fails
北伐を頓挫させん
Liu Dadao
劉大刀
You who came from afar
お前らと同じく
Noble volunteers
千里を奔り来たりし義士らが
Will all become eternal sinners
一旦罪人と為るを免れ得ぬぞ
Your Highness
殿下……
This
これは
I naturally trust Commander Liu
僕は劉統領を信ずれど
But I'm also afraid Commander Liu
劉統領の
Will misunderstand my intentions
誤解生じぬよう
That's why I specifically risked
こっそりと
Hiding my identity
身を隠し申した
To explain to Commander Liu
然るに来たりしは本心を明かし
And discuss a solution
共に策を練らんがためなり
Rise
さあ、起て
Your Highness's concerns
殿下のお憂え
I understand
拙者も承知仕り候
But Your Highness says
されど
There may be spies among my brothers
仲間たちの中に回し者ありと申すは
What's the evidence?
いかにして証明なさるか？